<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="76037" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Population Rebalance" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Tweaks cims' lifecycle for more balanced population and education needs." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="Tweaks cims' lifecycle for more balanced population and education needs." /-->
	<LongDescription>
Tweaks cims' lifecycle for more balanced population and education needs.

## Features

The mod has **many** features, most of them are **configurable**. Please see GitHub page for details and full description of features and parameters. The below list is only a short overview.

* **Lifecycle adjustments:** Default thresholds for licycle stages are changed from 21/36/84 to 12/20/75. This gives more realistic population structure.
* **Graduation logic:** Graduation process is more restrictive. Cims following typical education path will spend more time in High School, College and University.
* **New households:** Several fixes e.g. CoupleHousehold having only 1 Adult will now have 2 Adults. Fixes bugs where Children and Teens are all spawned with age 0 and all StudentHousehold are single Adults at age 36.
* **Dynamic education levels:** Until the first College is built, the cims will have an education adjusted to open jobs.
* **Birth process:** Adults cannot have children if they won't be able to raise them before becoming Seniors. Changes distribution of families towards less children, also lowers chances for consecutive children.
* **New Households limiter:** Limits spawning of new households when the number of empty properties falls below a configurable treshold (by default 1,5%). This allows for new Adults to have a chance to actually find a property.
* **Death process:** Cims will have a chance to die of old age once they become Elders. The chance of death increases with age.
* **Corpse removal:** Corpses have 50% chance to vanish.

## Comparison to the Vanilla game

* Less Elementary Schools, more High Schools and Colleges.
* Heavily reduced number of cims leaving the city (Moving Away).
* Number of cims incoming to the city will depend on ratio of free properties.
* There will always be free residential properties for new Adults.
* Less births (approx. 2/3 of vanilla level), much more deaths (approx. 3x more).

## Technical

* The options are applied only once, during the mod initialization. For new setting to take effect, you need to **restart the game**.
* Modified systems: AgingSystem, ApplyToSchoolSystem, BirthSystem, CitizenInitializeSystem, DeathCheckSystem, GraduationSystem, SchoolAISystem.

## Important Notes

* It will take one full in-game day for the population to adjust to the new thresholds. Education changes need more time, at least 3-5 days. You may wanna build a few extra High Schools until the levels will adjust.
* Cims cannot go back to the previous phase of their lives, so changes done by this mod are irreversible. Make sure to have a savefile. Once the mod is deactivated, cims will follow default logic, so eventually the city will return to the vanilla state, but it will take several in-game days.
* The timeline in CS2 is measured in days. Each in-game day also represents 1 month (e.g. when looking at average time spent in schools) and at the same time 1 year of the cim life. Cims live around 100 days, give or take few, so it is pretty close to average human lifespan.
* The population structure is based on EU statistics data, population by age. 0-14 years is ~15%, which we can consider Children in CS2 reality. 15-24 years is 11%, which we can consider Teens. And 65+ years is 21%, which we can consider Seniors (65 is usual retirement age in EU). The rest are Adults.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="docs/pop_change.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="docs/edu_change.png" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="Code Mod" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.9.1" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.1.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--<ChangeLog Value="v0.9.0 (2024-03-24) Mod ported to the official platform and updated for v1.1.0 of the game." />-->
	<ChangeLog>
v0.9.0 (2024-03-24)
* Mod migrated to PDXMods platform and updated for v1.1.0 of the game.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/Infixo/CS2-RealPop" />
</Publish>
